SYED TOUSIF

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

syedtousif1368@gmail.com

+91 9036262235

linkedin.com/in/syed-tousif-375a70190

Summary

Embedded Software Engineer with 5 years of experience in Development and Testing of Embedded Software in Avionics and Automotive domain.

Experience in Performing White Box Testing(Unit Testing) & Black Box Testing(Qualification Testing).

Experience in Embedded C ,C++ and Python coding programming language.

Involved in Testing, Analysis and review of Software Code and Requirements.

Identifying traceability gap between Software Requirement and Test Cases.

Experienced in Tools like IBM RTRT, Linux-Ubuntu WSL, QNX, Code Wright, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Polarion, Google Test, Cantata, Doors, Jenkins, GIT, Jama, Jira, Py-test. Bitbucket, Plastic SCM.

Experience



Software Engineer

Embitel Technologies

Dec 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

⊚ Software Engineer

L&T Technology Services
Mar 2021 - Nov 2022 (1 year 9 months)

Software Engineer

Cadmaxx Solutions Pvt Ltd 2020 - Dec 2020 (less than a year)

Software Engineer

Inventeron Technologies
Jan 2019 - Nov 2019 (11 months)

Education

Ghousia College of Engineering

Bachelor's degree, Electronics and Communications Engineering Jun 2013 - Jun 2018

New Millenium High School

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Skills

Jira • Embedded C • Python (Programming Language) • Language Skills • Embedded Software • AUTOSAR • Programming Languages • C++ • Testing • Embedded Systems